Juan Camilo Flórez Vanegas

jcflorezv@unal.edu.co | https://jcamilo.co | +57 322 326 67 29

EDUCATION

UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL **DE COLOMBIA**

COMPUTER SYSTEMS ENGINEERING 2016 - 2022 | Bogotá Cum. GPA: 4.3 / 5.0

SOCIAL MEDIA

LinkedIn:// VanJFlorez GitHub:// VanJFlorez GitLab:// VanJFlorez

CERTIFICATES

- B2 English Certification (IELTS)
- C1 English Certification (EF)
- Machine Learning with Big Data
- Convolutional Neural Networks
- Automate Stuff with Python
- Econometrics (University)
- Micro and Macroeconomics (University)
- Economic History (University)

Some entries are linked to the certificates.

SKILLS

Programming languages

• Java • C++ • JavaScript • TypeScript • SQL • Python • GNU/Bash • Batch Frameworks • Spring Boot • Quarkus • Django • EJB

JSF JPA (Hibernate) PrimeFaces • React/Material-UI • Bootstrap • Android SDK • NumPy • Scikit-Learn • Pandas • Boost C++ • KNIME • Spark

Tools and Protocols

• Git • Kubernetes • Azure • Docker • ElasticSearch • Jaeger • OpenShift • Azure DevOps • Apache Flink • Apache Kafka • Apache Flume • Apache Camel • JUnit • JMS • Mockito • Visual Studio • Tensorflow • SOAP UI • GNU-Linux • MongoDB • Oracle Database 11g • SQLite • PostgreSQL • MySQL • Power Designer • Virtual Box • Linux Servers • Audacity • Moodle • Maven • Gradle • SSH clients • Heroku • Jenkins • Google Compute Engine • TortoiseSVN • LATEX

Architectures and Metodologies

• Microservices • REST • Web Services • SOAP • DevOps (Azure) • Pipelining • Scrum • Good Practices (SOLID, Modularity, Design Patterns)

PROFILE

Computer systems engineer, software developer and computer programmer with 5 years of experience with proficient skills in debugging, mathematics, problem analysis, distributed computing and software design. He is an agile learner highly motivated by reaching goals. He is well versed in object oriented programming languages and has up-to-date skills in implementation techniques, software building and deployment.

In addition, he can understand efficiently libraries, frameworks, tools, conventions, engineering decisions and organizations businesses, since he reads with easeness software documentation from a wide range of applications which includes machine learning, computer graphics, optimization and applied mathematics. With a great sense of responsibility, commitment and good teamwork, he is committed with organization and team mission statements. He can speak spanish, english, portuguese and

RECENT EXPERIENCE

TERADIGIT GRAPHICS PROGRAMMING / DEBUGGING

SOFTWARE ENGINEER AND COMPUTER PROGRAMMER (SELF-EMPLOYED)

Jun 2023 - Current | Colombia

(Tools/Tech. stack) C++, Java11

- Disect ProjectM and Blender computer graphics source code.
- Debug Apache Tomcat and RedHat Hibernate source code.
- Implement a CPU based raytracer.

OPTUM ROOT CAUSE ANALYSIS / SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT AND MAINTENANCE / **SQL** Analysis and optimization

Manager Software Engineer

Oct 2022 - May 2023 | United States (remote)

(Tools/Tech. stack) SQL, Java EE 8, Spring Boot, Java Server Pages, JavaScript, Python - Fix a 40k USD/year finance report that was providing the wrong commision amounts.

- Found and fix bugs in Optum Financial core application (Root Cause Analysis).
- Advanced SQL analysis and optimizations.
- Full stack development; from SQL DDL/DML to JavaScript frontend code.
- Write software documentation.
- Debug and patch this 15+ year old application.

CREDERA STREAM PROCESSING / MICROSERVICES

SENIOR JAVA SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nov 2021 - Oct 2022 | United States (remote)

(Tools/Tech. stack) Kafka, Java 11, AWS, Postgres, Spring Boot, Kubernetes

- Re-implementation of Java7 legacy monoliths to Java11 microservices.
- Write several Kafka consumer-producers for the user-engagement streaming
- Microservices development with Spring Boot.
- Custom libraries development for microservices and ERP processing units that share the same business logic.
- Member of DE+I committee (marketing pillar).

CLARO BIGDATA PROCESSING / MICROSERVICES

JAVA SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Feb 2020 - Nov 2021 | Strazil (remote)

(Tools/Tech. stack) Java 11, Apache Flume - Flink - Kafka - Camel, MongoDB, Spring Boot, **OpenShift**

- Microservices development with Spring Boot, Quarkus and Django. Some examples
- can be seen here. - Big Data processing components using Apache Kafka, Flink, Flume and Camel.
- Batch Scripts and Java programs to automate Docker images builds and storage within Docker Hub cloud registry.
- Deployments in Openshift Container Platform pre-production environments. This includes scripts for builds and image stress tests.
- Provide mentorship for Junior and entry-level developers. - Take part as technical expert in 'MiClaro App' UI enhancements project.

ZYOS BACKEND MONOLITH DEVELOPER / SERVER SIDE UI DEVELOPER

FULLSTACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Jan 2019 - Feb 2020 | 💳 Colombia

(Tools/Tech. stack) EJB, JSF, Primefaces, JPA (Hibernate), Angular 9, JavaScript (ES6), Maven, Git, Apache TomCat

- Made improvements to Edificios Davivienda server software core features.
- Develop responsive front-end software and implemented some styling improvements
- Implemented from scratch several JavaScript components (notifications, ratings, snackbars) to improve the user experience.
- Backend software development to Mi Vivienda BCP server software in order to boost and correct bugs in edge execution cases. New functionalities to the overall application. Edificios Davivienda available here and Mi Vivienda BCP available here.

CENTRO DE PENSAMIENTO UNAL

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, REQUIREMENTS ENGINEER

Jun 2018 - Dec 2018 | Bogotá

(Tools/Tech. stack) Ruby, RubyOnRails, NGinX, PostgresSQL, Debian-Linux, Moodle, PHP, SSH, Heroku, Google Compute Engine, Git, Docker, Rancker

- Online course implementation with Moodle (available here) and a forum web application for that course with Thredded (available here). Full repository here.
- Requirements gathering on what software solution adapts better to the team needs.
- Customize the *Moodle* and *Thredded* deployments to meet the team requirements.

GRUPO SEPRO

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Jan 2018 - Jun 2018 | Bogotá

(Tools/Tech. stack) Python, Django, JavaScript, ExpressJS, Gunicorn, Apache HTTP Server, Git, VSCode, MySQL, Heroku

- Designed and implemented a survey information system that computes statistics and measurements over the answers submitted. This survey system was used to evaluate the Avocado and Sugar Cane derivatives supply chains performance from Cauca to Bogota.
- Coordinated a team of 3 undergraduate students to achieve the project goals. Two of them worked in software development and the another one worked in QA. Available here.